Inter-University Labor Education Committee Records 5234
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Inter-University Labor Education Committee Records
1951-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Inter-University Labor Education Committee
5234
12 cubic feet
12 linear ft.
Manuscripts (documents).
This accession consists generally of correspondence between the executive secretaries of the Inter-University Labor Education Committee (IULEC) and the staff of the participating universities, the Fund for Adult Education, and various labor unions; and reports and documents generated by the university projects and the administration of IULEC.
3337254
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 07, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 22, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The Inter-University Labor Education Committee (1951-1957) was created to promote cooperative educational programs between labor unions and the eight participating universities.
The Inter-University Labor Education Committee (IULEC) was organized in 1951 for the purpose of administering a grant from the Fund for Adult Education for experimental projects in workers' education. Eight universities participated in the grant, namely, the University of California at Los Angeles, Roosevelt University, Cornell University, the University of Chicago, the University of Illinois, the University of Wisconsin, Rutgers University and Pennsylvania State University.
The major purpose of the grant was to promote cooperative educational programs between labor unions and the eight participating universities in order to widen the extent and scope of labor activities to include foreign affairs, economics and community participation; to develop new techniques and tools to make education in these areas more effective and lasting; and to assist labor leaders in establishing and conducting educational programs within their organizations. The files reflect the role of the IULEC as a coordinating agency between the participating universities and labor and non-labor agencies; the activities of the participating universities; and projects in workers' education which were conducted by universities, government agencies and labor organizations in various states and foreign countries.
Scope and Contents
This accession consists generally of correspondence between the executive secretaries of the Inter-University Labor Education Committee (IULEC) and the staff of the participating universities, the Fund for Adult Education, and various labor unions; and reports and documents generated by the university projects and the administration of IULEC.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5545: National Institute of Labor Education (NILE) Papers 5767: National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records 5944: National Institute of Labor Education Additional Records
Educational fund raising--United States.; University extension--United States.; Adult education teachers.; Labor and laboring classes. Education. United States.; Labor and laboring classes. Scholarships, fellowships, etc. United States.; Public relations. Trade-unions. New York (State). Syracuse.; Public relations. Trade-unions. United States.; Rank and file participation.; Social services. New York (State). Syracuse. Citizen participation.; Social service. United States. Citizen participation.; Trade-union democracy.; Trade-union leadership. United States.; Trade-unions. New York (State). Social activity.; Trade-unions. New York (State). Utica. Social activity.; Trade-unions. United States. Social action.; Trade-unions. United States. Social activity.; Workers' compensation. United States.; Workers' education.; Workers' education. Agricultural workers. United States.; Workers' education. Denmark.; Workers' education. Iron and steel workers. United States.; Workers' education. United States.; Workers' education. White collar workers.; Workers' education. White collar workers. United States.; United States. Race relations.; AFL-CIO; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Teachers; American Friends Service Committee; American Labor Education Service; American Nurses Association; Brotherhood of Shoe and Allied Craftsmen. Rubber Sole and Heel Local.; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Committee for the Nation's Health; Cornell University; Corset and Brassiere Workers Union; Encampment for Citizenship; F.J. Murray Co.; Ford Foundation. Fund for Adult Education.; International Association of Machinists; International Brotherhood of Paper Makers; International Chemical Workers Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Printing Pressmen and Assistants' Union of North America; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (A.F. of L.); Inter-University Labor Education Committee.; Iowa Federation of Labor, AFL-CIO; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); Michigan State University; National Catholic Welfare Conference; National Labor Service; National Religion and Labor Foundation (U.S.); New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; New World Foundation; Pan American Union; Pennsylvania State University; Philadelphia Labor Education Council; Rocky Mountain Labor School; Roosevelt University; Rutgers University; Syracuse Industrial Council; Tennessee State Federation of Labor; Underwear and Negligee Workers Union; Unitarian Universalist Service Committee; United Mine Workers of America. District 50.; United Packinghouse Workers of America; United Paperworkers of America; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers of America; United States. Dept. of Labor.; United States. International Cooperation Administration.; United States. Mutual Security Agency; United States. Office of Labor Relations Advisor.; United States Information Agency; United States Technical and Economic Mission; University of Alabama; University of Illinois; University of Indiana; University of Manhattan; University of Manila. Labor Education Center.; University of Minnesota; Utica Federation of Labor; Barbash, Jack.; Berry, Guy; Brazeal, B.R. (Brailsford Reese); Brown, Theodore Henry, 1888-1973.; Brumm, John Moffett; Caldwell, John; Campbell, Ralph N. (Ralph Norton), 1910-; Carstens, Arthur; Catherwood, M. P. (Martin Paul), 1904-1978; Clement, Rufus E.; Coit, Eleanor G.; Conners, John D.; Cook, Alice Hanson; Donohue, Maurice F. X.; Douty, Agnes M.; Elder, Arthur H.; Emerson, Eleanor; Garman, Phillips, L.; Glazer, Joseph; Goldberg, Arthur J.; Golden, Clinton S. (Clinton Strong), 1888-1961; Greve, Florence Roehm; Guernsey, George; Henson, Francis; Higgins, George Thomas, 1924-1971; Hutchison, John; Kerr, Clark, 1911-2003; Kerrison, Irvine L. H. (Irvine Ledward Hamilton), 1916-; Liveright, A. A. (Alexander Albert), 1907-; Luchek, Anthony; Mates, John; McCallister, Frank; Mire, Joseph; Murray, Philip, 1886-1952; Pragan, Otto; Pyle, Hugh; Repas, Bob, 1921-; Rogin, Lawrence M.; Sexton, Brendan; Smith, Stanton E.; Soop, E. J.; Starr, Mark, 1894-1985; Sturmthal, Adolf Fox; Whitney, Beryl Albert, 1901-; Woll, Matthew, 1880-1956; Young, Edwin
3337254
- Minutes: Board of Directors, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes: Board of Directors, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes: Board of Directors, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes: IULEC Advisory Committee. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes: Evaluation Committee. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes: Operating Committee. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes: Regional Conferences. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minutes: Miscellaneous Meetings, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes: Miscellaneous Meetings, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- IULEC Progress Reports, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- California: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- California: Summary Reports. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chicago: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cornell: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cornell: Summary Report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cornell: Final Report. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Penn State: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Illinois: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Illinois: Final Report. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Roosevelt: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Roosevelt: Final Report. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Rutgers: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Rutgers: Final Report. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Wisconsin: Activity Reports. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- IULEC By-Laws (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lens proposal (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Publicity (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Publicity: Labor Education (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Publicity: Photographs (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Purposes, Objectives, Program (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Requests for Materials (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Speeches, Articles, etc. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Financial, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Financial, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- General Records, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  7/52- 4/9/53.
- General Records, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  4/17/53-8/4/53.
- General Records, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  8/14/53-12/8/53.
- General Records, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  12/17/53-4/20/54.
- General Records, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  4/29/54-9/28/56.
- General Records, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  4/4/55-9/15/55.
- General Records, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  9/15/55-11/16/55.
- General Records, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  12/1/55-2/8/56.
- Board of Directors and Operating Committee - General (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Campbell, Ralph: Chairman of Board, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Campbell, Ralph: Chairman of Board, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Campbell, Ralph: Chairman of Board, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Campbell, Ralph: Chairman of Board, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- IULEC Advisory Committee (Box 3, Folder 6)
- IULEC Evaluation Committee (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Labor Advisory Committees, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Overton, George - Attorney for IULEC, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Overton, George - Attorney for IULEC, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Overton, George - Attorney for IULEC, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- AFL Board Members, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- CIO Board Members, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- AFL-CIO Board Members, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Connors, John (AFL), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Connors, John (AFL), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Connors, John (AFL-CIO), 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Guernsey, George (CIO), 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Barbash, Jack: Special Consultant, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Cook, Alice: Special Consultant, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Douty, Agnes: Special Consultant, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Special Consultants: General, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Special Consultants: Reports, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Regional Conference: Atlanta, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  7/7/55.
- Regional Conference: California, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  8/1 and 3/55.
- Regional Conference: Cleveland, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  5/24/55.
- Regional Conference: Indianapolis, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  8/30/55.
- Regional Conference: Oklahoma, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  7/28/55.
- Blakely, Robert (FEA), 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Blakely, Robert (FEA), 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Blakely, Robert (FEA), 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Fund for Adult Education, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Fund for Adult Education, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Fund for Adult Education, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Fund for Adult Education, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Fund for Adult Education, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Fund for Adult Education, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Universities: General, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Universities: California, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Universities: California, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Universities: Montana Project, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Universities: Montana Project, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Universities: Montana Project, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  January/March, 1953.
- Universities: Montana Project, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  April/August, 1953.
- Universities: Montana Project, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  September/December, 1953.
- Universities: Montana Project, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Universities: Montana Project, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Universities: Montana Project, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Universities: Chicago, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Universities: Chicago, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Universities: Chicago, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  January/May, 1953.
- Universities: Chicago, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  June/December, 1953.
- Universities: Chicago, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Universities: Chicago, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Universities: Cornell, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Universities: Cornell, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  January/April, 1953
- Universities: Cornell, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  May/December, 1953
- Universities: Cornell, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Universities: Cornell, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Universities: Illinois, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Universities: Illinois, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Universities: Illinois, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Universities: Illinois, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Universities: Illinois, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Universities: Illinois, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Universities: Penn State, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Universities: Penn State, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Universities: Penn State, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Universities: Penn State, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Universities: Penn State, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Universities: Roosevelt, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Universities: Roosevelt, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Universities: Roosevelt, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Universities: Roosevelt, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Universities: Roosevelt, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Universities: Rutgers, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Universities: Rutgers, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  January/June, 1953.
- Universities: Rutgers, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  July/December, 1953.
- Universities: Rutgers, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Universities: Rutgers, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Universities: Rutgers, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Universities: Wisconsin, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Universities: Wisconsin, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Universities: Wisconsin, 1955-1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Universities: Alabama, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Universities: Indiana, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Universities: Manhattan, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Universities: Michigan State, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Universities: Minnesota, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Universities: General, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- AFL, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- AFL, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- AFL, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- AFL, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- AFL, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- CIO, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- CIO, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- CIO, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- AFL-CIO, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- AFL-CIO: Headquarter, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- AFL-CIO: Headquarter, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- AFL-CIO: Unions, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  January/May, 1956
- AFL-CIO: Unions, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  June/December, 1956
- AFL-CIO: Unions, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- AFL-CIO: Independents, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Mult Education Association, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- American Friends Service Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- American Labor Education Service, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- American Labor Education Service, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- American Labor Education Service, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- American Labor Education Service, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  January/July, 1955
- American Labor Education Service, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  August/December, -1955
- American Labor Education Service, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  January/March, 1956
- American Labor Education Service, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  April/December, 1956
- American Labor Education Service, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Institute of International Education, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Institute of International Education, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- International Labor Office, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Government Agencies, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Mutual Security Agency, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- National Labor Service, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- National Religion and Labor Foundation, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Fan American Union, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Philadelphia Labor Education Council, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- State Deparments of Vocational Education, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- U. S. Department of Labor, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- U. S. Department of Labor, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- U. S. Information Agency, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Contacts: Libraries, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Contacts: Libraries, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Contacts: Libraries, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Contacts: Universities, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Contacts: Universities, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Contacts: Universities, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Contacts: Interested Agencies, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Contacts: Interested Agencies, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Contacts: Interested Agencies, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Contacts: Foundations, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  May/June, 1953.
- General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  July/December, 1953
- General Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- General Correspondence, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- General Correspondence: Foreign Friends, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- General Correspondence: Labor Education, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Labor Education (Box 8, Folder 10)
  First Draft
- Labor Education (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Revised Draft
- Labor Education (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Final Draft (Printed Copy)
- Teaching Aids and Publications, California (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Chicago: Attitude Survey. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Chicago: World Affairs I. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Chicago: World Affairs II. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Cornell. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Roosevelt. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Rutgers. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Teaching Aids and Publications,Wisconsin. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- IULEC: Bibliographies (Box 9, Folder 6)
- IULEC: Barbash Report, Outline. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- IULEC: Chapter Drafts. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- IULEC: Draft Manuscript. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- IULEC: Correspondence. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- IULEC: Conferences. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- IULEC: Contacts. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- IULEC: Correspondence., 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- IULEC: Correspondence., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- IULEC: Correspondence., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- IULEC: Final Report. (Box 9, Folder 16)
- IULEC: Financial. (Box 9, Folder 17)
- IULEC: Health. Multi-phasic Screening. (Box 9, Folder 18)
- IULEC: History and Development. (Box 9, Folder 19)
- IULEC: Mire Report, Correspondence I. (Box 9, Folder 20)
- IULEC: Mire Report, Correspondence II. (Box 9, Folder 21)
- IULEC: Draft Materials. (Box 9, Folder 22)
- IULEC: Operating Committee - E. Emerson. (Box 9, Folder 23)
- IULEC: Procedures. (Box 9, Folder 24)
- IULEC :Project Proposals. (Box 9, Folder 25)
- IULEC: Progress Reports. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- IULEC: Quarterly Reports (Box 10, Folder 2)
- IULEC: School Policy. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- IULEC: Summary Project Report (Box 10, Folder 4)
- IULEC: Teachers Meetings. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- IULEC: Teachers. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- IULEC: Teaching Materials. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Jamestown (Box 10, Folder 8)
- New York City: Local #3, IBEW (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Olean: Correspondence and Progress Report, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Olean: Correspondence and Progress Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Olean: Class Reports. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Olean: Course Materials. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Olean: News clippings. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Olean: Rent Controls Project. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Rochester. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Syracuse: Progress Reports, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Syracuse: Progress Reports, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  January/May, 1953
- Syracuse: Progress Reports, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  June/December, 1953
- Syracuse: Progress Reports, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Syracuse: AFL, Mixed. (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Syracuse: AFL - AFT Research In Government Affairs. (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Syracuse: Amalgamated Clothing Workers. (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Syracuse: American Federation of Teachers. (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Syracuse: Basic Building Trades Council, AFL (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Syracuse: Building Laborers. (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Syracuse: CIO Research in Community Affairs. (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Syracuse: CIO Sewage Committee, Correspondence end (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Syracuse: Progress Reports. (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Syracuse: Progress Reports: CIO Sewage Committee, News clippings. (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Syracuse: Progress Reports: CIO Sewage Committee, Research Materials. (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Syracuse: Progress Reports: District 50, United Mine Workers. (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Syracuse: IBEW (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Syracuse: Joint Labor Group - AFL, CIO, RRB, UMW. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Syracuse: Steelworkers, Group I, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Syracuse: Steelworkers, Group I, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Syracuse: Steelworkers, Group II, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Syracuse: Steelworkers, Group II, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Syracuse: United Auto Workers. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Syracuse: United Packinghouse Workers. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Syracuse: United Packinghouse Workers. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Utica: Correspondence and Progress Reports. (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Utica: AFL. (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Utica: AFL Community Action. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Utica: AFL Mixed Group. (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Utica: AFL Public Speaking. (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Utica: AFL Community Research (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Utica: CIO, Eskow Group. (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Utica: CIO, Rosenthal Group. (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Utica: CIO, Child and Family Guidance. (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Utica: IAM (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Utica: News clippings. (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Outline for Proposed Publication. (Box 11, Folder 21)
- "Labor and the Community. " (Box 11, Folder 22)
  Draft
- "Labor Participation in Community Affairs." (Box 11, Folder 23)
  FirstMimeographedDraft
- "Labor Participation in Community Affairs." (Box 11, Folder 24)
  SecondMimeographedDraft
- "Labor's Role in Community Affairs." (Box 11, Folder 25)
  FinalPrintedCopy
- Correspondence. R. N. Campbell, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Correspondence. R. N. Campbell, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Correspondence. R. N. Campbell, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Correspondence. R. N. Campbell, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Correspondence. R. N. Campbell, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- IULEC: Book I, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  July-October, 1951.
- IULEC: Book II, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  January-March, 1952.
- IULEC: Book III, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  May-June, 1952
- IULEC: Book IV, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  September-December, 1952